clearcompany.com 2015-03-25

# Privacy Policy - Real-Time Talent Alignment Platform

Revised: Oct. 23, 2012

Privacy Statement

WHAT DOES CLEARCOMPANY HRM (HEREAFTER KNOWN AS “HRM DIRECT, INC.”) DO WITH YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?

Who:

HRM Direct, Inc. (HRM) is a software company based in Boston, MA, USA. HRM provides software that companies use to make their recruiting processes more efficient and to comply with government regulations. HRM is solely a software company and is not a recruiting firm or staffing agency. HRM is a US-based company founded in 2004. For more information, visit <http://www.clearcompany.com/company/>

Where:

HRM software is provided to clients as a Web-based service similar to webmail or online banking. Information is stored on servers owned or leased by HRM.

What:

When you apply for a job at a company that uses HRM, our software collects your job application, resume, and other information used by that company as part of their recruiting process. Recruiters, managers, and other people involved in the hiring process will log into our software to review job applications and to track the status of each applicant.

Why:

All companies are required to gather certain information in order to evaluate job applicants, and in some cases, to report to government agencies to comply with regulations, such as those prohibiting discrimination by race or gender.

**Information Collection and Use**

Personal Information   
Personal Information is information which can be used to uniquely and personally identify you. This includes your first and last name, full home address, government-issued ID numbers such as a passport or driver’s license number, phone number, or email address. Data about you which cannot be used to identify you as an individual, such as your city of residence, is not considered to be “Personal Information.”

Applying for a Job   
In order to apply for a job with a company that uses HRM, you must submit the information requested by that company in the manner they choose. This may include either emailing a resume, or creating a profile and submitting an application package with or without a resume. The information gathered during this process is specified entirely by our client, and is intended solely for their own use.

How We Protect Your Information   
The security of your Personal Information is important to us. When applying for a job through HRM, we encrypt your information using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology. Our production servers are dedicated servers managed by Logicworks, Inc., at datacenters located in the New York and New Jersey metropolitan area. Logicworks is a SAS 70 Level II compliant provider and maintains safeguards on both physical and online access to our servers including the use of firewalls and Virtual Private Networks. HRM employees are required to sign non-disclosure and confidentiality agreements and are trained to protect Personal Information at all times.

We follow or exceed generally-accepted industry standards to protect the Personal Information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission of storage is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we use commercially-acceptable means to protect your personal information, it is impossible for us to guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on HRM, you can email your question to [support@clearcompany.com](mailto:support@clearcompany.com "ClearCompany HRM Support"). ￼￼￼￼

￼Cookies   
A Cookie is a small file stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. Cookies are used for a wide variety of purposes within the HRM software and while you may disable cookies, we cannot guarantee that all parts of the system will function properly if you do. HRM will not share your Personal Information with third parties through the use of Cookies, clear GIFs, “Web Bugs,” or other tracking mechanisms.

Uses of Information  
When HRM’s software gathers Personal Information, it is solely for the use our client as part of their recruiting or human resource processes. HRM will not share your Personal Information with third parties, except in the following situations:

  * _Background Screening or Assessment Services_ : Some employers will perform background or reference checks on job applicants, or use pre-employment tests as part of their hiring process. In these cases, your information may be shared with a third-party vendor(s) who perform those services.
  * _Aggregated Data Products_ : HRM may create data products by analyzing data and trends across multiple clients. For instance, HRM might create salary estimates for specific cities or job titles based on information submitted by applicants. By definition, these data products are based on the pooling of information from large samples of people, and are stripped of any Personal Information. Currently, HRM does not develop or sell any products based on aggregated data, but may do so in the future.
  * _As part of an onboarding process_ : If you are hired by a company which uses HRM, we may share your information with other vendors used by that company in the course of their normal HR processes. For example, your contact information and SSN might be shared with a payroll service.
  * _With a government agency, when required by law_ : HRM will provide information to government agencies if required to do so by law or court order.
  * _With subcontracted internal service providers_ : HRM may engage subcontractors for certain operational or other business functions. In this event, these third parties shall not be entitled to access or make use of Personal Information except in direct support of HRM’s business and for the purposes as stated in this Privacy Statement. Currently, the only third party with this access is Logicworks, Inc., a New York City-based company responsible for managing our servers.

**Changes in this Privacy Statement**   
If this Privacy Statement is changed, we will post those changes to our homepage or other areas where this Statement is distributed.

**Opting Out**   
Currently, HRM does not share any information with third parties except as previously described. You may permanently opt out of all third-party sharing (except with permitted government agencies), including future sharing not covered in this Statement, by sending an email to support@hrmdirect.com with the subject line OPT OUT. Please include your first and last name, the name of the company whose job you applied to through HRM, and the email address you used when applying. Please note that in order to withdraw your application for employment, you must contact the company’s HR or recruiting department directly. We will reply by email to confirm your request to opt out.

**Safe Harbor Protections for European Union and Swiss Residents**   
HRM complies with the US-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the US-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries. HRM has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view our certification page, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>

In compliance with the US-EU Safe Harbor Principles and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles, HRM commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. EU or Swiss citizens with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact us through [support@clearompany.com](mailto:support@clearcompany.com). You will receive an ￼￼￼￼automated reply to acknowledge that your inquiry has been received. HRM staff will review and respond to your message within 14 days.

HRM has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by HRM, please visit the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR web site at www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints for more information and to file a complaint.
